<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>金沢 直晃</title><link>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/</link><description>Recent content on 金沢 直晃</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research Award: 第13回ロボティクスシンポジア研究奨励賞を受賞しました</title><link>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/posts/robosym28-research-encouragement-award/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/posts/robosym28-research-encouragement-award/</guid><description>仙台で行われた第41回日本ロボット学会学術講演会(RSJ2023)の表彰式で，第13回ロボティクスシンポジア研究奨励賞を頂きました．
これを励みにこれからも精進していきます！
発表内容 見出しへのリンク 今回賞を頂いたのは，2023年3月に行われた第28回ロボティクスシンポジアでの「調理支援ロボットの視覚-言語モデル時系列利用によるレシピ記述からの食材状態変化認識」の発表です．</description></item><item><title>Research Work: Recognition of Heat-Induced Food State Changes by Time-Series Use of Vision-Language Model for Cooking Robot</title><link>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/posts/ias18-2023-cook-vlm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/posts/ias18-2023-cook-vlm/</guid><description>Our work Recognition of Heat-Induced Food State Changes by Time-Series Use of Vision-Language Model for Cooking Robot (Accepted at IAS18-2023) has been made public. Paper Link
Abstract 見出しへのリンク Cooking tasks are characterized by large changes in the state of the food, which is one of the major challenges in robot execution of cooking tasks. In particular, cooking using a stove to apply heat to the foodstuff causes many special state changes that are not seen in other tasks, making it difficult to design a recognizer.</description></item><item><title>自己紹介</title><link>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/about/</guid><description> 金沢 直晃 見出しへのリンク 東京大学大学院 情報理工学系研究科 知能機械情報学専攻 情報システム工学研究室 博士課程の金沢直晃です．
家庭や施設，ホテルや店舗，工場など色々な場所でロボットが活躍し，人の生活や社会を支える未来の実現を目指して，実世界でタスクを実行できるロボットの知能の研究をしています． 現在は生活支援ロボット，特に調理支援ロボットの認識・行動・計画・学習の研究をしています．
経歴 見出しへのリンク 2024-, 日本学術振興会特別研究員(DC2) 2023-, 東京大学大学院 情報理工学系研究科 知能機械情報学専攻 博士課程在学中 2021-2023, 東京大学大学院 情報理工学系研究科 知能機械情報学専攻 修士課程修了 2017-2021, 東京大学 工学部 機械情報工学科 卒業</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/publications/</guid><description>International Journal Papers 見出しへのリンク Y. Obinata, K. Kawaharazuka, N. Kanazawa, N. Yamaguchi, N. Tsukamoto, I. Yanokura, S. Kitagawa, K. Okada, M. Inaba. &amp;ldquo;Situation classification of living environment by daily life support robot using pre-trained large-scale vision-language model&amp;rdquo;, Advanced Robotics (AR), vol.39, no.7, pp.323-337, 2025. Paper Link
N. Kanazawa, K. Kawaharazuka, Y. Obinata, K. Okada, M. Inaba. &amp;ldquo;Real-world cooking robot system from recipes based on food state recognition using foundation models and PDDL&amp;rdquo;, Advanced Robotics (AR), vol.</description></item><item><title>成果</title><link>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/publications/</guid><description>こちらのページをご覧ください．</description></item><item><title>連絡先</title><link>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kanazawanaoaki.github.io/ja/contact/</guid><description>kanazawa [at] jsk.imi.i.u-tokyo.ac.jp までメールでご連絡ください．</description></item></channel></rss>